To whom it may concern,

I am writing this letter to express my desire to teach design at BYU-Hawaii. I believe I am uniquely prepared to effectively grow the design program at BYU-Hawaii. In particular, I have unique experience with and interest in teaching students to:

- 1) work as a member of a diverse team
- 2) design effectively with and for technology
- 3) create conceptual meaning in their work

November 2014 MARK PARSON

tolmark@gmail.com (208) 315-2311 In many ways, I've spent the majority of the past ten years immersed in the startup world. I have worked as a design consultant for many startups & businesses. I have also had the opportunity to cofound several startups and new products. Most of these have been glorious failures—a few have achieved substantial success. Regardless, I have learned much from the need to collaborate with individuals of diverse background. In most of the teams I've worked on, I've represented the design arm of our efforts. Perhaps the most rewarding (and at times frustrating) aspect of collaboration has been the expanding experience of being thrust against the opinions and viewpoints of individuals vastly different from myself. I have learned to respect and value other's points-of-view while simultaneously lobbying for and defending the needs of design. I have experienced the thrill that comes when seemingly opposite talents and personalities become complementary and mutually reinforcing—and would love to teach my students to experience the same.

I have always found myself drawn to technology–specifically to the creative act of programming. While design is perhaps my first love, I find great joy in coding elegant interactive work. The interactive medium is uniquely suited for representing information beautifully and responding intelligently to the user. I find the ability to program very useful in small projects or in executing quick experimental prototypes. I stay on the design side of the fence on larger projects, but find having a working knowledge of computer science allows me to push the boundaries of what is possible and work effectively with developers. While a good interactive designer need not learn to program they should fully understand the psychology of the user, and the technical potential of the medium.

Finally, I love intelligent concept driven design. Design that spirals out of good thinking excites me more than work that is simply beautiful. Learning how to express the visual language beautifully is of course critical for the design student. However, I believe learning to design with wit and intelligence sets a designer apart from her peers in this incredibly competitive field. I am confident there will always be work for designers who can think critically.

I recognize the great potential a teacher holds to impact the lives of their students for good or ill. I am grateful for the many teachers who have impacted me for good and opened my eyes to things of beauty. I hope to be such a teacher.

Thank you very much for your time.

Make Jamen

Kind regards!

Mark Parson

MARK PARSON

tolmark@gmail.com (208) 351-2311 172 Birch Avenue Rexburg, ID 83449

EXPERIENCE

PAGODABOX • REXBURG, ID

Interactive Director / Co-Founder: 2010 - Present

Cofounded tech startup Pagodabox. I lead our interaction design team and work closely with our talented team of engineers. I have architected a dynamic online brand and elegant admin UI that has been instrumental in attracting over 30k users. The design has garnered hundreds of positive tweets and allowed us to compete with much larger competitors before our actual product was complete.

TINY BRICK . DALLAS, TX - REXBURG, ID

Interactive Director / Co-Founder: 2009 - 2010

Cofounded Tiny Brick and designed the brand / interactive strategy. Though we launched Tiny Brick in the noisy Magento module space, its clean unique design set it apart and attracted an investment entity which purchased the Tiny Brick in large part for its market share and the solid brand we had established.

THE DELORUM GROUP . SEATTLE, WA - REXBURG, ID

Interactive Director / Founding Partner: 2004 - 2012 (still involved as an advisor) Founded The Delorum Group with two partners. I oversee online brand strategy, interactive design, and technology. I have worked to create an environment of mutual respect where our developers and designers successfully collaborate on cutting edge projects for large clients such as Zumiez Skateboarding, Tommy Bahama Clothing, Bevy, Idahoan Potatoes etc.

UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON . SEATTLE, WA

Guest Lecturer: Flash / Interaction Design: 2006

Lectured on basic principles of interaction design as they applied to creating interactive content with Adobe Flash.

LINDSTROM DESIGN . LOS ANGELES, CA

Designer: 2002 - 2004

Responsibilities included managing/designing various print, branding, packaging and web projects from start to finish. Art directed and implemented a wide range of interactive pieces.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON

Masters of Fine Arts in Visual Communication Design: emph. UX Design: June 2007

BRIGHAM YOUNG UNIVERSITY - IDAHO

Bachelor of Fine Arts in Graphic Design: August 2005

MISC SOFTWARE / DEVELOPMENT IMAGE CREATION
Guest Lecturer BYUI Expert in Adobe CS Illustration

NW Addys - Silver Expert Coffeescript / git Hand Drawn Letterforms

Expert HTML5 / CSS3 Photography

Object Oriented Development